

**UX/UI DESIGNER** 



Vancouver, BC



andreaho.ca



andrea.ks.ho@gmail.com



778.882.7372

# **SKILLS**

User Experience Design

User Interface Design

Market Research

Empathetic Research

Competitor Analysis

Information Architecture

Low/Mid/High Fidelity Wireframes

Interaction Design

Rapid Prototyping

**Usability Testing** 

Graphic Design

Brand & Identity

Typography

Iconography

HTML5/CSS3

## **TOOLS**

Sketch

Invision

Marvel

Adobe Creative Suite

Principle

Usability Hub

Microsoft Office

Github

Pen & Paper

Slack

JIRA

Figma

My mission is to create a happier, stress-free, educational environment for everyone through user experience. With my background in marketing, I place heavy emphasis on understanding how people behave in all of my design projects. It is only through heavy knowledge of humans when we start to solve the world's problems.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### User Experience Design Intern, Terramera

Vancouver, BC

Nov 2017 - Current

- Designed user flows based on personas created from empathy interviews
- Improved Information Architecture after executing card sorting exercises, stakeholder interviews and user interviews
- Produced multiple low and high fidelity wireframes of internal and external websites in an Agile environment
- Optimized site behaviour for desktop, tablet and mobile through Google Analytics and user testing
- Communicated closely with the marketing team to create a consistent brand style

#### Marketing Intern, Boucher Institute of Naturopathic Medicine

Vancouver, BC

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

- Created a tactical brief for the Professional Development Project and 7 copy decks for the redesign of poster advertisements
- Designed 4 different catalogue covers for the clinic and faculty institute using Adobe Illustrator
- Worked closely with the graphic designer to create a cohesive program for the incoming medical students, including logo design and branding

## **EDUCATION**

### User Experience Academy, Designlab

San Francisco, CA

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

I worked over 500 hours within the intensive 6 month UX Academy program, with the guidance of an experienced mentor and the sharing within the student community, to learn essential skills to produce three quality hands-on projects.

- Conducted user interviews and collected market research information to create personas, empathy maps, and customer journey maps
- Used card sorting exercises to make informed information architecture, sitemap and userflow decisions
- Low to High-fidelity wireframes were iterated following the results of usability tests on prototypes
- Created brands, logos and icon designs that aligned with the target audiences' personalities

#### My Achievements Include

- Trekit A social mobile app that allows for quick and easy sharing of memories created from travellers' trips
- NASA Vacations A personalized screen for every passenger on the NASA aircraft for space tourism
- ShopFresh A responsive website for an online grocery store catered to busy university students using Sketch

# Bachelor of Commerce - Marketing, University of British Columbia

Vancouver, BC

Sept 2013 - Apr 2017

#### **UBC Alma Mater Society: The Nest**

I created a design brief, in a team of 4, which aimed to increase the optimization of space of the main student building at the University of British Columbia.

- Examined research studies and conducted observational research to find the overarching problem of misalignment of offerings provided in the building
- Executed the Offering-Acitivity Culture Map and Compelling Experience Map to understand how to interact with the two main target student types, what motivates them, and how to follow up with their building space experience